<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jacob Likins</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jacob Likins</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>clemson_internship.txt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/clemson_intern/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/clemson_intern/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Between my junior and senior year of high school, I interned at Clemson University&amp;rsquo;s International Center for Automotive Research (ICAR) in their robotics lab. I worked on a team of college students to create a robot that used machine learning to complete that year&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vexrobotics.com/competition?srsltid=AfmBOopaRRBhTduATjxg90Smleq9xV1jfcVkNqG2RwVNgNpbg2HHuEAf&#34;&gt;VEX Robotics Competition challenge&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-overview&#34;&gt;Project Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The goal of the project was to create a robot that could autonomously navigate a field and complete tasks such as picking up and placing objects, while also avoiding obstacles. We also wanted to create a VEX AI team for Clemson University to compete in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>client_website.txt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/website_design/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/website_design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I developed a fully custom website for &lt;strong&gt;Will&amp;rsquo;s Remodeling&lt;/strong&gt;, focusing on creating a modern, responsive, and high-performance online presence. This project involved close collaboration with the client to meet their specific qualifications and deliver a product that perfectly matched their vision.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-goals&#34;&gt;Project Goals&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The primary goal was to create a professional portfolio and increase online presence for a local remodeling company to build trust between the company and potential clients. Key requirements included:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>custom_PCBs.txt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/pcb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/pcb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During my first year on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.olinelectricmotorsports.com&#34;&gt;Olin&amp;rsquo;s Formula SAE Team&lt;/a&gt;, I designed and implemented &lt;strong&gt;three custom PCB boards&lt;/strong&gt; for our electric vehicle: the &lt;strong&gt;throttle board&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;precharge and discharge board&lt;/strong&gt;, and the &lt;strong&gt;battery management system (BMS) board&lt;/strong&gt;. I utilized &lt;strong&gt;KiCAD&lt;/strong&gt;, an open-source PCB design software, which enabled the use of specialized components and custom footprints.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;battery-management-systems-board&#34;&gt;Battery Management Systems Board&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first board I developed was our &lt;strong&gt;Battery Management System (BMS) board&lt;/strong&gt;. This critical system is responsible for &lt;strong&gt;monitoring the voltage and temperature of each cell&lt;/strong&gt; in our battery pack, as well as &lt;strong&gt;balancing the cells&lt;/strong&gt; to ensure voltage parity. This is crucial for the safety and longevity of the battery pack and prevents overheating.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>remote_controlled_golf_cart.txt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/remote_controlled_golfcart/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/remote_controlled_golfcart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I contributed to a golf cart project that could be &lt;strong&gt;controlled remotely using an Xbox controller&lt;/strong&gt;. This project was undertaken during my time as a high school student at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scgssm.org/&#34;&gt;South Carolina Governor&amp;rsquo;s School for Science and Mathematics&lt;/a&gt; (GSSM). As the project was initiated before my involvement, I &lt;strong&gt;integrated with the existing work&lt;/strong&gt; of previous students.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/golfcart/full_golfcart.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Full view of the remote controlled golf cart&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-inherited&#34;&gt;What We Inherited&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Previous students had already made significant progress, having &lt;strong&gt;acquired a golf cart&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;integrated actuators for electronic control of the steering column and brake pedal&lt;/strong&gt;. They had also planned a main control box to centralize the wiring. Facing limited documentation, we &lt;strong&gt;reverse-engineered the existing wiring&lt;/strong&gt; using the golf cart&amp;rsquo;s wiring diagram and a multimeter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>type_race.txt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/type_race/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/type_race/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Type-Race is an engaging typing game &lt;strong&gt;built in Python using the &lt;code&gt;pygame&lt;/code&gt; library&lt;/strong&gt; by my partner and me. Inspired by &amp;ldquo;Type Racer,&amp;rdquo; it&amp;rsquo;s designed to &lt;strong&gt;help users improve their typing speed and accuracy&lt;/strong&gt; through a fun, competitive experience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-game&#34;&gt;The Game&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The game challenges players to &lt;strong&gt;copy as much of the on-screen prompt as possible within a 60-second timeframe&lt;/strong&gt;. The prompt dynamically scrolls as the player types. Mistakes are visually underlined in red for easy correction using the backspace key. The top-left display provides real-time feedback on the &lt;strong&gt;remaining time&lt;/strong&gt;, the player&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;current words per minute (WPM)&lt;/strong&gt;, and, in multiplayer mode, the &lt;strong&gt;opponent&amp;rsquo;s WPM&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;display: flex; gap: 2rem; align-items: flex-start; flex-wrap: wrap;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/jacob.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 300px; border-radius: 8px;&#34; /&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div style=&#34;max-width: 600px;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;Hi there! I&#39;m &lt;strong&gt;Jacob Likins&lt;/strong&gt;, an electrical and computer engineering student at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.olin.edu&#34;&gt;Olin College&lt;/a&gt;, passionate about building impactful technology through hands-on engineering and collaborative innovation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;I&#39;m the &lt;strong&gt;Electrical Lead&lt;/strong&gt; for our Formula SAE EV team, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.olinelectricmotorsports.com&#34;&gt;Olin Electric Motorsports&lt;/a&gt;, where I lead the development of critical vehicle systems like battery management, throttle control, and high-voltage power electronics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;I also conducted &lt;strong&gt;robotic simulation research at Clemson University&lt;/strong&gt;, modeling autonomous systems and exploring intelligent control in complex environments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
